## SWETA VASHI

## JR. FRONT-END DEVELOPER/ SCRUM MASTER/ EDUCATION MANAGEMENT & TRAINER

Website - <a href="https://swetavashi.github.io/SwetaPortfolio/">https://swetavashi.github.io/SwetaPortfolio/</a>

Email- <a href="mailto:sweta.y.vashi@gmail.com">sweta.y.vashi@gmail.com</a> | Phone - (+46) 734905328 | LinkedIn- <a href="mailto:linkedIn-linkedIn

GitHub -https://github.com/SwetaVashi

Address - 1401, Skytteholmsvagen 7C, Solna, Sweden 17144

#### **PROFILE**

 Professional IT trainer with extensive experience in various technical courses like MERN stack, C, C++, .NET, Python, DBMS, CG, SDLC, Software Engineering etc. An expert at designing training courses with technical content, I am effective at imparting knowledge through my superior verbal communication skills and active listening style. I have proven success in utilizing cutting-edge technology to devise training exercises for all types of learners.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# October 2020 - Core Faculty and Scrum Master, Codify College AB, Sweden January 2021

- Mentored the bootcamp as Core Faculty for 16 weeks MERN Stack course.
- Scrum Master for learners' projects like E-Commerce
  Website, Project tracker, Portfolio, Weather API, To Do list,
  expense tracker etc. developed on MERN platform.
- Prepare all training material for courses, including PowerPoint presentations, skill exploration and exercises, and assessments.
- Train technical learners in developing in Website with MERN.
- Conduct training on site and via video conferencing.
- Supervise the scheduling of training programs while remaining flexible to new training demands.
- Gauge the effectiveness of training programs and adjust for optimal results.

## June 2008 – March 2020

#### Trainer IT and Scrum Master, Mumbai University, India

- Professional IT Trainer for learners by teaching various IT courses.
- Scrum Master for learners' projects on various platforms.
- Assessed the training needs of individuals as well as work teams.
- Created lesson plans tailored to employee needs.
- Delivered classroom-based training on the Microsoft suite of products such as Microsoft Office, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint for entry-level technical staff.
- Created classroom materials to facilitate skills training.
- Developed practice exercises for experiential learners.
- Gave feedback to class participants and provided individual coaching as needed.
- Provided assistance to the support department with end-user refresher training

## August 2007 – April 2008

## Process Associate, HSBC Bank, India

- Enhancement / Automation of Report generation using Excel VBA macros. Optimized data collection procedures and generated reports on a weekly, monthly, and quarterly basis.
- Used advanced Microsoft Excel to create pivot tables and pivot reporting, as well as use VLOOKUP function. Loan files processing, Verification of the data gaps and enrichment. Report generation for default management.

## **EDUCATION**

Mumbai University, Mumbai, India

2005 - 2007: Masters of Science in Computer Science 2002 - 2005: Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Web Skills: CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript (Vanilla), ES6, Node JS, React JS, MVC, web standards and accessibility, crossbrowser compatibility and Bootstrap 4,5
- Basic skills: PHP, C, C++, Python, SQL, Mongo DB, Agile, UML, JIRA.
- Web Tools: VS Code, FileZilla, Git
- Application Software: MS Office Suite, Microsoft Excel
- Content Management Systems: Basic WordPress.
- Operating Systems: Windows
- Languages: English (Professional), Hindi (Native), Swedish (Elementary)
- Subjects Taught: Software Engineering, Software Project Management, Database Management Systems, Python Programing, HTML5, JavaScript, Adv. SQL, Computer Graphics, C, C++, Advance Excel, C#, .Net
- **Soft Skills**: Management Skills, Coaching, Public Speaking, Leadership Skill, Presentation giving, Motivational Skills.

### **AWARDS AND RECOGNITION**

Received thanks awards for cross functional assistance to reporting users for data enrichment & automation at HSBC Mumbai, India. (2007 & 08).

#### REFERENCES

1) Anurag Garg, Swed Bank, Sweden

Phone: +46 734769931

2) Bindu Trikha, Codify College AB, Sweden

Phone: +47 40969175